Erik John Clark

After having been a pilot and commissioned officer in the Royal Air Force (RAF), Erik left to study Avionic Systems Engineering at university and lead all group projects tasked of him. Erik has a keen interest in the future of technology, demonstrated with his commended experimental work at university, a MSc project in place of his BEng project and has been undertaking a PhD in advanced target tracking techniques since, also serving in the British Army in an elite unit. Erik is determined to achieve as much as he can in his lifetime so he can help shape society in a way that helps all, and not just a few.



@erikjclark



London, UK



erik_clark@protonmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Support Engineer

CMR Surgical

Apr 2021 – Apr 2022

- Network troubleshooting across multiple global sites and robot interfaces.
- Downloading and uploading data to AWS cloud.
- Redesigned the work process for the team's primary role, company-wide.
- Triage, escalation and investigation.
- Rewrote service level agreement with internal customers.
- CAPA investigation.
- Designed team training plan.
- Working within an Agile framework.

COVID Compliance Officer

Bernard Matthews

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

- Generated presentations and weekly reports for executives.
- Chairperson for executive meetings.
- Research, propose and enforce COVID policy across multiple sites.

Tutor

Brilliant Club

Mar 2019 – July 2019

- Taught an extracurricular physics course about infrared light.
- Students of ages 13-15 year old.

Infantry

British Army Reserve

Jun 2015 – Aug 2021

- Member of UK Armed Forces elite combat unit.
- Qualified sharpshooter.
- Worked with sensitive communication systems.
- Worked in small teams in confined arduous environments.
- Worked with the recruitment training team.
- Defence Train The Trainer (DTTT) qualification.

Summer Internship (Systems)

GE Aviation

2013 & 2014

 Above and Beyond Silver Global Award for distinguished contribution to customer critical project.

- Allocated to a 'tiger team' on a high profile project where customer relations were at risk.
- Authored numerous legal compliance documents.
- Authored and reviewed documentation to ARP 4754A DAL A standard.
- Wrote, and tested software to DO-178C DAL A standard.
- Led validation team for Remote Interface Unit.
- Started unique complex inter-unit communication analysis project.
- Created, configured, tested and integrated RIU internal test procedure in C programming language.
- Experience on R&D project.

Student

University of Liverpool

Sep 2012 – Mar 2022

- Student representative
- Studied towards PhD in Advanced Object Tracking Techniques.
- Farnell Electronic Component Company Prize 2013/2014.
- 2nd place in local IET Present Around the World Competition.
- 2nd place in Year 2 Project Video surveillance from a UAV.
- Presented student project to DSTL.

Pilot

Royal Air Force

Jun 2007 - Aug 2012

- Awarded Permanent Commission.
- · Formal speeches.
- Completed rotary flying training mental agility, personal organisation, stress handling for prolonged periods.
- Reviewed Major Accident Control Regulations document for highly strategic military base.
- Revised Nuclear Incident Plan for UK military base.
- Military Skills Course high stress situations.
- Completed Platoon Commanders Battle Course high stress situations.

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Software:

- C, Python, HTML5, CSS3, MATLAB, PowerShell.
- Secure Linux server setup.
- Website development.
- DOORS: Requirements management software.
- Presented conference paper at Fusion 2017.
- Various leadership roles: IET (All committee roles),
 Athena Swan outreach ambassador, university senate council, charity committee.
- Customer communications.

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- 2005: Gold CREST Award from British Association of the Engineering Education Scheme in England.
- 2008: RAF Officer Training Completed Level 5 Diploma: Leadership and Management.
- 2010: RAF: Completed Military Helicopter Flying Training.
- 2011: British Army: Officer Training Course.
- 2014: GE Aviation: Skilled Level Architecture course.
- 2014: GE Aviation: Requirements Capture Course.
- 2015: University of Liverpool: Avionic Systems Engineering - 1st Class BEng (Hons).
- 2021: British Army: Defence phase 3 trainer.
- 2022: AiCore: Machine Learning and MLOps.
- 2022: Microsoft: Building MS Teams Integrations and Workflows.
- 2022: Microsoft: Manging Windows and Surface devices.
- 2022: Microsoft: DevOps with GitHub.
- 2022: Microsoft: Protect Data and Manage Risk.
- 2022: Microsoft: AI Fundamentals.
- 2022: Microsoft: Enable Hybrid Work with MS Teams.
- 2022: Microsoft: Modernise Security and analyse threats.
- 2022: Microsoft: Manage your Frontline Workforce.
- 2022: Microsoft: Fundamentals of security, compliance and identity.
- 2022: Microsoft: Zero Trust.
- 2022: SANS: Fundamentals of Culture and Organisational Change.
- 2022: SANS: Motivating Change.
- 2022: SANS: Enabling and Measuring Change.
- 2022: SANS: Developing your Business Case.
- 2023: Agile Project Leadership.
- 2023: Project Management Foundations.
- 2023: Supporting workers with disabilities.
- 2023: ArcX Cyber Threat Intelligence 101.

INTERESTS

- Fitness: running, gym, Krav Maga.
- Charity.
- Researching technology: AI, quantum computing.
- Piano.

CLEARANCES AND REFERENCES

• Upon request.